<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?> 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>
<!--?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?-->
<p:plan xmlns:p="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p:release projectid="m2e" version="0.13.0"/>
  <p:introduction>
    <p>M2E provides both a framework for building Maven-centric Eclipse
      tools and set of tools and user interface elements directly
      consumable by Eclipse Users.</p>
    <div>
      <p>As a framework, M2E provides facilities to import and configure
        Maven projects in Eclipse workspace as well as APIs that allow
        m2e extensions to access Maven project metadata and participate in
        Maven project configuration and workspace build.</p>
    </div>
    <div>
      For the end user, M2E provides:
      <ul>
        <li>wizards to import existing and to create new Maven projects
        </li>
        <li>rich form-based and text-based pom.xml file editor</li>
        <li>launch configuration type to launch Maven build directly
          from Eclipse IDE
        </li>
        <li>access Maven repository index to browse repository contents
          and in various code-assist
        </li>
      </ul>
    </div>
    <p>Extensible JDT integration is provided by M2E as well.</p>
  </p:introduction>
  <p:release_deliverables>
    <ul>
      <li>feature to be installed into an Eclipse IDE installation using
        an update site.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p:release_deliverables>
  <p:release_milestones>
    <p:preamble>
      <p>
        Release milestones will be occurring at roughly 6 week
        intervals, and will be aligned with the
        <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/Indigo_Simultaneous_Release">
          Indigo Simultaneous Release
        </a>
        train.
      </p>
    </p:preamble>
    <p:milestone date="02/07/2011" milestone="M5">
      <div>0.13.0 M5</div>
    </p:milestone>
    <p:milestone date="03/14/2011" milestone="M6">
      <div>0.13.0 M6</div>
    </p:milestone>
    <p:milestone date="05/02/2011" milestone="M7">
      <div>0.13.0 M7</div>
    </p:milestone>
  </p:release_milestones>

  <p:target_environments>
    <p>M2E requires minimum Java SE 5 VM.</p>
    <p>M2E is compatible with Eclipse 3.5.2, Eclipse 3.6.2 and Eclipse
      3.7 and is generally expected to work on each of these Eclipse
      releases respective referenced platforms with additional
      requirement of Java SE 5 or better VM.
    </p>
    <p:internationalization>
      <p>All m2e user interface elements are externalized, but only
        English strings are provided as the default resource
        bundles.
      </p>
    </p:internationalization>
  </p:target_environments>

  <p:compatibility_with_previous_releases>
    <h3>Compatibility with Sonatype m2eclipse 0.10.x and earlier
      m2eclipse releases
    </h3>
    <p>
      <strong>API Contract Compatibility:</strong>
      To comply with Eclipse Foundation requirements, all m2e java package
      and extension points have been moved to org.eclipse.m2e
      namespace. No compatibility layer will be provided for consumers
      of earlier versions of m2eclipse.
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>Workspace Compatibility:</strong>
      No migration will be provided for workspaces created with earlier
      versions of m2eclipse. Sharing of the same workspace with m2e
      0.13.0 and earlier versions of m2eclipse will not be supported.
      The users are expected to start with new workspace and import
      their projects using "Existing Maven Projects" import wizards.
    </p>
  </p:compatibility_with_previous_releases>

  <p:themes_and_priorities>
    <p:preamble>
    </p:preamble>
    <p:theme name="Robust build lifecycle mapping">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <strong>Metadata driven lifecycle mapping.</strong>
            M2E will define lifecycle mapping metadata format and
            mechanisms to embed mapping metadata in project pom.xml
            files, share mapping metadata among multiple related
            projects and provide mapping metadata via Eclipse extension 
            point.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
      <p:proposed>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <strong>Public lifecycle mapping API.</strong>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p:proposed>
    </p:theme>
    <p:theme name="Discovery and installation of extensions">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <strong>Find and install required extension.</strong>
          M2E will only support limited number of standard Maven plugins
          out of the box, while support for other Maven plugins is
          expected to be provided by thirdparty extension. M2E will
          provide discovery mechanism that will help users find and
          install extensions required to support their projects.
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
    </p:theme>
    <p:theme name="Better pom.xml editor">
      <p:committed>
        <p>TBD</p>
      </p:committed>
    </p:theme>
    <p:theme name="Stay current with Maven technologies">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <strong>Include latest released Maven version</strong>
            Maven is an active opensource project with new release
            produced at roughly six weeks intervals. To maintain parity
            with bugfixes and new features available to command line
            Maven users, m2e will include latest Maven version available
            in time for Ingigo release. We will work with Maven core
            developers to align m2e and maven release schedules.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
      <p:proposed>
        <ul>
          <li>Mechanism to deliver Maven Core updates</li>
        </ul>
      </p:proposed>
    </p:theme>
    <p:theme name="Mature Eclipse.org project">
      <p:committed>
        <ul>
          <li>Move m2e project to Eclipse Foundation</li>
        </ul>
      </p:committed>
      <p:proposed>
        <ul>
          <li>Join "Java" eclipse distribution</li>
          <li>Graduate from incubation</li>
        </ul>
      </p:proposed>
    </p:theme>
  </p:themes_and_priorities>
</p:plan>
